Links

- Portfolio
- Star Project
- ∠ LinkedIn

Skills

Expert:

- React
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- ' React Ouery
- HTML5 + CSS3 + SASS
- Styled Components
- ✓ Material-UI
- ✓ Jest
- Cypress
- React Testing Library

Advanced:

- ✓ Node.is
- ✓ AWS Cognito
- ✓ AWS DynamoDB
- ✓ Supabase
- ✓ REST
- ✓ Sentry
- ✓ Jira
- ✓ Figma

Intermediate:

- Tailwind CSS
- ✓ Next.js
- GraphQL
- ✓ PostgreSQL
- ✓ SOL
- ✓ MongoDB
- ✓ Prisma
- ✓ Datadoa

Basic:

- ✓ Pvthon
- ✓ Linux

LLMS - Maps - Charts:

- Open AI
- Leaflet
- Recharts

Main Soft Skills

- Analytical problem solving
- Attention to detail
- Teamwork

Languages

Good Fluent

English

German French Portuguese Catalan

Spanish

Hugo Carvalho

Frontend Engineer

Highly motivated self-taught programmer, with 4 years of experience building responsive applications within the React ecosystem. I bring a detail-oriented approach and a commitment to delivering efficient solutions that prioritize exceptional user experience, driven by a passion for programming that led to a successful career change.

hugo.berlinlife@gmail.com

+49 176 78 29 31 87

10437 Berlin

Work Experience

Berlin, Germany (2021 - 2024)

HERITAS GMBH (ERBLOTSE)

Germany's first digital product for inheritance and creation of last will. Team size: 4-6.

06/2023 - 08/2024 - Software Developer

02/2021 - 05/2023 - Junior Software Developer

Extensive experience within a small, agile team, contributing to two distinct products with diverse tech stacks. Key accomplishments include:

- Implemented critical and non critical features aligned with business objectives.
- Refactored and optimized code for improved readability and maintainability.
- Implemented and maintained comprehensive test suites to ensure code quality.
- Diagnosed and fixed issues identified by Sentry or Datadog.
- Fostered effective communication and collaboration among team members, product manager, and external web designers.
- Actively participated in technical discussions, contributing valuable insights.
- Conducted code reviews, providing constructive feedback.

Tech: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, AWS, GraphQI, PostgreSQL, React Query, Node.js, Prisma, Material UI, CSS3, Styled Components, I18n, Cypress, Jest, React Testing Library, Sentry, Datadog, Jira, Figma.

Birte Gall 7 1st

Co-Founder Erblotse

Hugo is easy to work with, diligent in his work and fun to be around. When asked to contribute to new projects he is always open to wrap his head around it and willing to work his way through new challenges arising. Hugo helped bring a platform to live, without any precedent we could follow.

I am impressed by his discipline in constantly teaching himself new things. He is a valuable team member in a tech team.

Christian Fischer · 1st

Engineering Manager | Empowering Teams to Drive Innovation and Excellence at Ströer

I had the opportunity to manage Hugo on my team, where he made solid contributions, particularly in frontend development with React and TypeScript. Hugo quickly developed proficiency in these technologies and consistently delivered reliable code.

What stood out most about Hugo was his ability to work well within the team. He was always willing to collaborate and support colleagues, which had positive impact on our projects.

Related Experience

Engineered and deployed multiple personal projects, notably Cafes & You, a full-stack application comprising over 10,000 lines of code. For demonstration purposes, you can explore the application, without sign up, by using the following credential: test@user.com / 1234567 .

Tech: React, TypeScript, React Query, Supabase, PostgreSQL, Material UI, Leaflet, Nominatim API, Cypress, Netlify.

Other Work Experience

Berlin, Germany (2009 - 2020)

04/2013 - 03/2020 - Hotel Gat Point Charlie - Receptionist and reservations agent

06/2010 - 03/2012 - Hotel Gat Point Charlie - Receptionist

Barcelona, Spain (2005 – 2009)

04/2008 - 03/2009 - Hotel Barceló Atenea Mar - Receptionist

12/2005 - 01/2008 - JVC (Victor Company of Japan) - Customer Care Agent (inbound)

Lisbon, Portugal (2004 – 2005)

09/2004 - 06/2005 - CESOP - Call center team supervisor for opinion surveys

Education

Portugal, Lisbon

Master in Sociology (2004)

Lisbon University Institute (ISCTE), Lisbon